Happy New Year!
新年快乐！
For many in the UK, if the New Year means anything, it means starting with a clean slate and turning over a new leaf.
对许多英国人来说，新年若有什么意义，那便是重新开始、改过自新。
And to do this, many of us make New Year's resolutions – a list of ways that we intend to improve ourselves in the year ahead.
为此，我们许多人会制定新年决心——一份计划在来年提升自我的清单。
We reflect on our past transgressions and resolve not to do them again.
我们反思过去的过错，决心不再重犯。
Refraining from smoking is ever popular, as is a vow to take up more exercise or spend more time with family.
戒烟向来很受欢迎，发誓要更多地锻炼身体或花更多的时间陪伴家人也同样常见。
But where does the idea of a New Year's resolution come from?
但新年决心的想法源自何处呢？
The answer might lie 4,000 years ago in ancient Babylonia, according to History.com.
据History.com网站记载，答案或许能追溯到4000年前的古代巴比伦。
The Babylonians are believed to be the first to hold recorded celebrations for the New Year.
人们认为巴比伦人是最早有记载庆祝新年的民族。
The 12-day-long celebration, Akitu, allowed them not only to reaffirm their loyalty to the king, or crown a new one, but also to pledge to the gods to pay their debts and return borrowed objects.
这场长达12天的庆典名为“Akitu”，在庆典中，他们不仅会重申对国王的忠诚（或为新国王加冕），还会向诸神发誓偿还债务、归还借来的物品。
For their 'good behaviour', they believed the gods would bestow favour upon them for the year to come. If not, there would be divine consequences!
他们相信，凭借这种“良好行为”，诸神会在来年赐福于他们；否则，将面临神的惩罚！
The Romans too had similar traditions.
罗马人也有类似的传统。
New Year's Day was a time when senators would swear they had upheld the laws and city leaders and soldiers would take an oath of loyalty to the emperor.
新年当天，参议员会宣誓维护法律，城市官员和士兵会宣誓效忠皇帝。
Incidentally, the month of January, is named after the Roman god Janus.
顺便说一句，一月（January）以罗马神雅努斯（Janus）命名。
He is the god of beginnings, transitions and time, among other things and is depicted as having two faces – one looking to the past and the other facing forward to the future.
雅努斯是开端、过渡和时间等等之神，被描绘为有两张脸——一张回望过去，另一张展望未来。
The Romans may be long gone, but their legacy lives on.
罗马人早已消逝，但他们的传统留存至今。
Come the turn of the year, our eyes turn inwards. We look at self-improvement, review our past mistakes, confess our wrongdoings, seek atonement and try to sharpen up in general.
岁末年初，我们开始向内审视：关注自我提升，回顾过往错误，坦陈过失，寻求赎罪，并努力全面改进。
Ultimately, much like the Babylonians and Romans, we seek to reaffirm the best parts of ourselves, while leaving the dross behind.
最终，和巴比伦人、罗马人一样，我们试图肯定自身最美好的部分，同时摒弃糟粕。
Whether you're looking at a quick behavioural tweak, or a huge personality overhaul, you're taking part in a tradition that goes back centuries.
无论你是想快速改善行为，还是彻底重塑性格，你都在参与一项可追溯数百年的传统。
I wish you all the best sticking to your resolutions.
祝愿大家都能坚持自己的决心。
Happy New Year!
新年快乐！